<resources>
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">Scorecard</string>

    <!-- Activity Titles -->
    <string name="title_about">About</string>
    <string name="title_game_setup">%1$s Setup</string>
    <string name="title_rules">How to Play</string>
    <string name="title_scorekeeper">%1$s Scorekeeper</string>
    <string name="title_select_game">Select Game</string>
    <string name="title_enter_scores">Enter Scores</string>
    <!-- End Activity Titles -->

    <!-- About Activity -->
    <string name="text_about_version">Scorecard Version %1$s</string>
    <string name="text_about_copyright">
        &#169;%1$d Willem Paul
        \nAll Rights Reserved.
        \n
        \nThis application may not be distributed without the developer\'s explicit permission.
    </string>
    <!-- End About Activity -->

    <!-- Game Setup Activity -->
    <!-- End Game Setup Activity -->

    <!-- New Game Activity -->
    <string name="text_welcome">Welcome to Scorecard!</string>
    <string name="content_desc_new_game_button">Start a new game</string>
    <string name="text_new_game">Tap to start a new game</string>
    <!-- End New Game Activity -->

    <!-- Rules Activity (Generic) -->
    <string name="text_rules_header_1">Getting Started</string>
    <string name="text_rules_header_2">Playing the Game</string>
    <string name="text_rules_header_3">Scoring</string>
    <string name="text_rules_header_4">Winning the Game</string>
    <!-- Rules Activity (Generic) -->

    <!-- Rules Activity (Euchre) -->
    <string name="text_rules_body_1_euchre">
        To play Euchre, you need four players in two teams of two, a standard, 52-card deck of,
        playing cards, and something you can use to keep score (such as this app).
        \n
        \nTeam members are seated across from one another.
        \n
        \nBefore you begin, remove all cards less than 9 from the deck (i.e. 2 through 8). You will
        not use those cards at all.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_2_euchre">
        Chose the first dealer however you like. That player shuffles the deck and deals it out
        evenly among all players in alternating groups of two and three cards. Each player should
        have five cards in his or her hand after dealing.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_1_euchre">
        For example, if Player 1 is the dealer, he or she deals two cards to Player 2, three to
        Player 3, two to Player 4, three to him- or herself, then three to Player 2, and so on.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_3_euchre">
        After dealing, there will be four cards remaining. Turn the top card of this pile over and
        place the pile in the middle.
        \n
        \nEach player, starting with the player to the dealer\'s left, now has the opportunity to
        call the round\'s trump suit based on the face-up card in the center. If he or she wishes to
        do so, the dealer must take the face-up card and replace one card in his or her hand with it
        (i.e. by placing a different card from his or her hand face-down on the pile).\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_2_euchre">
        For example, if the face-up card is the A&#x2665; and Player 3 calls the trump suit, then
        the dealer takes the A&#x2665; and adds it into his or her hand. Then, he or she must
        remove a different card from his or her hand, for example, the 9&#x2660;, and place it
        face-down on the pile. &#x2665; is now the trump suit for that round.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_4_euchre">
        If the first player (to the left of the dealer) does not wish to call the trump suit, he
        or she may pass, and the decision now goes to the player to his or her left.
        \n
        \nThis continues until either the dealer has taken the face-up card or until all four
        players have passed. If the dealer takes the face-up card, that card\'s suit is now the
        trump suit for the round. If not, starting with the player to the dealer\'s left, each
        player has the opportunity to call the round\'s trump suit by naming a suit.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_3_euchre">
        Tip: Calling the trump suit, whether by making the dealer take the face-up card or by naming
        the suit, should be based off of the cards in your hand.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text">
        The player to dealer\'s left plays first. He or she places a card from his or her hand
        face-up in the middle. Continuing to the left, each player plays a card from his or her hand
        in the same manner. However, each player must play a card in the same suit as the leading
        card (the first card played) if possible. If a player does not have a card in the leading
        suit, then he or she may play any card.\n
    </string>
    <!-- End Rules Activity (Euchre) -->

    <!-- Rules Activity (Nerts) -->
    <string name="text_rules_body_1_nerts">
        To play Nerts, you need any number of players, a standard, 52-card deck of playing cards for
        each player, and something you can use to keep score (such as this app).\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_1_nerts">Be sure that each deck has a <i>different</i> back design.
        Thereason for this will be explained later.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_2_nerts">
        Each player shuffles his or her deck and places the top 13 cards face-up in a pile. This is
        that player\'s Nerts pile. Then, he or she places four cards face-up in a row next to the
        Nerts pile.
        \n
        \nThe four cards in a row can be played onto following the rules of Solitaire:\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_2_nerts">
        A player may stack a card on top of another card if the card being played is of the opposite
        color and has a value one lower than the card below it.
        \n
        \nFor example, if the lowest card in the stack is the Q&#x2665;, you may stack either the
        J&#x2660; or the J&#x2663; on it.
        \n
        \nA player may move one stack onto another, provided this rule is not broken. Players may
        not play a card underneath another card.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_3_nerts">
        Aces (A) are played in the middle of all players. Again, these cards are played onto
        following the rules of Solitaire, with a twist: Any player may play onto the cards in the
        middle.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_3_nerts">
        A player may stack a card on top of another card if the card being played is of the same
        suit as and has a value exactly one greater than the card below it.
        \n
        \nFor example, if an A&#x2660; is in the middle, any player may play a 2&#x2660; on it. Any
        player may then play a 3&#x2660; on the stack and so on.
        \n
        \nTip: It is helpful to flip over a pile when playing the King (K) of that pile, so that
        players can more easily know that the pile has been completed.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_4_nerts">
        If multiple players attempt to play the same card onto a pile, the card that reaches the
        pile first stays, while the other cards must be taken back.
        \n
        \nAny cards that are not in the starting 17 are kept in a face-down deck. Players use these
        cards by drawing three at a time and playing the cards in order from top to bottom, if
        possible.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_4_nerts">
        For example, if a player draws 6&#x2663;, K&#x2665;, and 9&#x2660;, in that order, he or she
        must play the 9&#x2660; before the K&#x2665; and the K&#x2665; before the 6&#x2663;.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_5_nerts">If a player cannot play the top card of the cards he or
        she has drawn, then he or she may draw three more cards and continue this process. If a
        player has drawn all the cards in his or her deck, that player takes the drawn cards, flips
        the pile face-down, and may continue drawing cards.
        \n
        \nPlayers may use the top card of their Nerts pile as normal, with one exception: The top
        card of the Nerts pile may <i>not</i> be played in the individual Solitaire area (the row of
        four cards in front of each player) unless there is an open space in the row, in which case
        the card may be placed in that space.
        \n
        \nPlay continues in this way until a player plays all 13 cards from his or her Nerts pile
        and calls out, \"Nerts!\"\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_5_nerts">
        If multiple players call \"Nerts!\" at the about the same time, it is up to the other
        players to determine whether one player called \"Nerts!\" first or if the players tie.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_6_nerts">
        After a player calls \"Nerts!\", players may not play any more cards. Any cards being played
        as \"Nerts!\" is called must be taken back.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_7_nerts">
        The cards in the middle are sorted by player, that is, by the cards\' back designs, and each
        player counts the number of cards he or she played in the middle. Each player then subtracts
        from that amount the number of cards remaining in his or her Nerts pile. This number is that
        player\'s round total.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_6_nerts">
        For example, if a player played 16 cards in the middle and had 5 cards remaining in his or
        her Nerts pile, that player\'s round total would be 11 points.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_8_nerts">
        This number is then added onto the player\'s previous score to form that player\'s new total
        score.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_9_nerts">
        Play continues in this way until one or more players reach or exceed a winning point value.
        This value can be any amount, though 100 points is a good amount. The player with the most
        points wins the game.
    </string>
    <!-- End Rules Activity (Nerts) -->

    <!-- Rules Activity (Rich Cards) -->
    <string name="text_rules_body_1_rich_cards">
        To play Rich Cards, you need four or more players, a standard, 52-card deck of playing cards
        without the Jokers, and something you can use to keep score (such as this app).\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_1_rich_cards">
        Although you can play with any number of players (up to 52, at least), it is not recommended
        to play with more than seven; it is best to play with four players, since no cards must be
        removed. If the group is larger than seven, consider splitting into multiple groups.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_2_rich_cards">
        You will need a number of cards evenly divisible by the number of players. This means that
        you may need to remove some cards from the deck before you begin.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_2_rich_cards">
        <b>4 Players:</b> Use all 52 cards
        \n<b>5 Players:</b> Use 50 cards
        \n<b>6 Players:</b> Use 48 cards
        \n<b>7 Players:</b> Use 49 cards
        \nAnd so on.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_3_rich_cards">
        Do not remove just any cards, as doing so will affect the scoring.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_3_rich_cards">
        Here are some examples of cards that are OK to remove:
        \n<b>5 Players:</b> 6&#x2663;, 6&#x2666;
        \n<b>6 Players:</b> 5&#x2666;, 6&#x2660;, 7&#x2663;, 6&#x2666;
        \n<b>7 Players:</b> 5&#x2660;, 6&#x2666;, 7&#x2663;\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_4_rich_cards">
        Should you choose to remove cards other than these, make sure not to remove any &#x2665;
        cards (See <b>Scoring</b>). If possible, don\'t remove high- or low-value cards, such as
        Aces (A), 2s, Jacks (J), etc.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_5_rich_cards">
        Chose the first dealer however you like. That player shuffles the deck and deals it out
        evenly among all players.
        \n
        \nThe player to dealer\'s left plays first. He or she places a card from his or her hand
        face-up in the middle. This card\'s suit is the trump suit for the trick. Continuing to the
        left, each player plays a card from his or her hand in the same manner. However, each player
        must play a card of the trump suit if possible. If a player does not have a card in the
        trump suit, then he or she may play any card.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_4_rich_cards">
        For example, if Player 1 plays the 4&#x2663;, then every player must play a &#x2663; if he
        or she has a &#x2663; in his or her hand. If, however, Player 3 has no &#x2663;s, then he
        or she may instead play a &#x2666;.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_6_rich_cards">
        Once all players have played a card, the player who played the highest-valued card in the
        trump suit&#x2014;Aces are high&#x2014;takes the trick (all the cards played that round).\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_5_rich_cards">
        For example, if the cards in the trick are:
        \n<b>Player 1:</b> 6&#x2665;,
        \n<b>Player 2:</b> 3&#x2665;,
        \n<b>Player 3:</b> J&#x2660;, and
        \n<b>Player 4:</b> 7&#x2665;;
        \nthen Player 4 takes the trick. Even though Player 3\'s J&#x2660; has a higher value, it is
        not in the leading suit (&#x2665;) and is therefore not considered when determining who
        takes the trick.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_7_rich_cards">
        The player who took the trick then leads the next one.
        \n
        \nPlay continues in this way until either all cards have been played or there are no more
        possible points in the round (See <b>Scoring</b>). After the round is over, the player to the
        left of the previous round\'s dealer becomes the dealer for the new round.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_8_rich_cards">
        There are six rounds in a game, each with its own scoring method. The rounds are scored as
        follows:\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_6_rich_cards">
        <b>Round 1:</b> 10 points for each trick.
        \n<b>Round 2:</b> 10 points for each &#x2665; card.
        \n<b>Round 3:</b> 25 points for each Queen (Q) card.
        \n<b>Round 4:</b> 100 points for the K&#x2660;.
        \n<b>Round 5:</b> 100 points for the last trick.
        \n<b>Round 6:</b> Use all previous scoring methods.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_9_rich_cards">
        Note that in Rounds 2, 3, and 4, it is possible to finish the round before all cards have
        been played. If there are no more cards left in players\' hands that are worth points, then
        the round is over.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_hint_7_rich_cards">
        For example, in Round 4, if a player takes the K&#x2660; in the fifth trick, then the round
        is over, because the K&#x2660; is the only card worth points.\n
    </string>

    <string name="text_rules_body_10_rich_cards">
        At the end of the game, each player\'s scores are added together to produce that player\'s
        final score. The player with the <i>fewest</i> points wins the game.
    </string>
    <!-- End Rules Activity (Rich Cards) -->

    <!-- Scorekeeper Activity -->
    <string name="text_first_round">Initial Scores</string>
    <string name="text_round">Round %1$d Scores</string>
    <!-- End Scorekeeper Activity -->

    <!-- Game Setup RV Adapter -->
    <string name="text_game_setup_rv_adapter_team">Team %1$d</string>
    <!-- End Game Setup RV Adapter -->

    <!-- Select Game RV Adapter -->
    <string name="text_select_game_rv_adapter_players_value">Players: %1$d</string>
    <string name="text_select_game_rv_adapter_players_unlimited">Players: %1$d or more</string>
    <string name="text_select_game_rv_adapter_players_range">Players: %1$d to %2$d</string>
    <string name="text_select_game_rv_adapter_teams_none">Teams: None</string>
    <string name="text_select_game_rv_adapter_teams">Teams: %1$d teams of %2$d</string>
    <!-- End Select Game RV Adapter -->

    <!-- Simple Score RV Adapter -->
    <string name="text_simple_score_rv_adapter_hint">Score</string>
    <!-- End Simple Score RV Adapter -->

    <!-- Add Player Dialog -->
    <string name="text_add_player_title">Add Player</string>
    <string name="text_add_player_hint">Name</string>
    <!-- End Add Player Dialog -->

    <!-- Ask Edit Player Dialog -->
    <string name="text_ask_edit_player_title">Edit %1$s?</string>
    <!-- End Ask Edit Player Dialog -->

    <!-- Edit Player Dialog -->
    <string name="text_edit_player_title">Edit Player</string>
    <string name="text_edit_player_hint_rename">Name</string>
    <!-- End Edit Player Dialog -->

    <!-- Info Dialog (Game Setup Activity) -->
    <string name="dialog_title_error">Oops!</string>
    <string name="dialog_title_confirm">Wait!</string>
    <string name="text_error_ppt_not_valid">It looks like the teams aren\'t even.</string>

    <string name="text_confirm_np_out_of_range">
        There are currently %1$d players in the game. However, it is recommended to play with at
        most %2$d. Do you still want to continue?
    </string>
    <!-- End Info Dialog (Game Setup Activity) -->

    <!-- Info Dialog (Select Game Activity) -->
    <string name="text_game_info_euchre">
        Euchre is a plain-trick game. Teams try to win three of the five tricks per round, with the
        goal of reaching ten points.
    </string>

    <string name="text_game_info_nerts">
        Nerts is a highly competitive patience game. Players try to get rid of all the cards in
        their Nerts piles by playing onto common piles.
    </string>

    <string name="text_game_info_rich_cards">
        Rich Cards is a plain-trick game with a twist: Each of the six rounds has its own scoring
        method and thus, its own strategy.
    </string>
    <!-- End Info Dialog (Select Game Activity) -->

    <!-- General Dialog Strings -->
    <string name="text_select_team_spinner_prompt">Select Team</string>
    <string name="text_select_team_spinner_team">Team %1$d</string>
    <!-- End General Dialog Strings -->

    <!-- Game Strings -->
    <string name="team_name">Team %1$d</string>
    <!-- End Game Strings -->

    <!-- Menu Actions -->
    <string name="menu_action_rules">Rules</string>
    <string name="menu_action_about">About</string>
    <!-- End Menu Actions -->

    <!-- General Strings -->
    <string name="int_string" translatable="false">%1$d</string>
    <string name="plus_minus" translatable="false">&#x00b1;</string>
    <string name="ok">OK</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="edit">Edit</string>
    <string name="delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="yes">Yes</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>
    <string name="list_and">\ and\ </string>
    <string name="list_comma">,\ </string>
    <string name="list_comma_and">, and\ </string>
    <!-- End General Strings -->
</resources>
